Karla Villa Estrella

408.830.4116 | kvillaestrella@horizon.csueastbay.edu | www.karlavilla.me

SKILLS

Languages: Java, C/C++, Python, HTML, CSS

Technologies: GitHub, Git, Linux, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, Android Studio

Soft Skills: Strong interpersonal and emotional intelligence, attention to detail, time management, adaptability

PROJECTS

MyShell

Developed a simple shell interface that uses parent/child processes to perform the commands. Also used signals to communicated with processes.

Languages and Tools: C, Linux

Journeys

Jouneys is an android app that tracks a user's walking or running route. Used Google Maps API to play around with tracking and mapping the route. Used Google Realtime Database to save the routes of the users. Used Firebase Authentication to set up the login system in the app.

Languages and Tools: Java, Android Studio, ItelliJ, Google RealTime Database, Firebase Authentication, Google Play Store API, Google Maps API

Dogs vs Cats

Created a model to solve the image classification model of cats vs dogs. The model is trained with over 4,000 images of cats and dogs. The model decides whether the image is a dog or a cat.

Languages and Tools: Python, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Jupyter Notebook

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

JPMorgan Chase & Co Software Engineering Virtual Experience Program Participant 2022 - 7hrs

Participated in the open access JPMorgan Chase & Co Software Engineering Virtual Experince with Forage Tasks completed: Setting up my web development environment, fixed broken client data feed scripts by making the required adjustments and added unit tests, modified typescript files to make the web application output correct based on the requirements, modified typescript files to modify the live graph web application based on the requirements. Languages and Tools: Python, Typescript, Git, Web Applications

WORK EXPERIENCE

New Americans Fellow - Santa Clara County, Office of Immigrant Relations

06/2023 - 08/2023

As a fellow we get to explore the inequalities that are active in the immigrant community in the Bay Area. We are conducting reasearch on the voices of immigrants. Our goal is to have their voices heard and their contributions acknowledged.

Coding Instructor - *Athena Coding(contract)*

01/2023 - 3/2023

Taught children the fundamentals of programming using Minecraft and Roblox.

Student Researcher - RUMBA

09/2020 - 04/2021

Conducted research on food desserts in the Bay Area. Collected data from the Census Bureau and USDA to track low income areas and areas without a grocery store in a 10-mile radius.

Languages and Tools: Python, Jupyter Notebook

EDUCATION

California State University, East Bay

08/2020 - 05/2023